{
    "title": "Application Security",
    "description": "Gain comprehensive knowledge of safeguarding applications with this guide. Explore techniques and practices to protect software from threats.",
    "quiz":  [
        {
            "question": "What is the primary goal of application security?",
            "options": [
                "To ensure software is easy to use",
                "To safeguard applications from vulnerabilities",
                "To make applications faster",
                "To enhance user experience"
            ],
            "_answer": "To safeguard applications from vulnerabilities"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which phase of the Secure Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) involves identifying security requirements early?",
            "options": [
                "Requirements Gathering",
                "Design",
                "Development",
                "Testing"
            ],
            "_answer": "Requirements Gathering"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does Static Application Security Testing (SAST) analyze?",
            "options": [
                "Running application",
                "Source code",
                "Network traffic",
                "User behavior"
            ],
            "_answer": "Source code"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the purpose of Dynamic Application Security Testing (DAST)?",
            "options": [
                "Analyzing code without executing it",
                "Testing running applications for vulnerabilities",
                "Reviewing code manually",
                "Simulating attacks"
            ],
            "_answer": "Testing running applications for vulnerabilities"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the purpose of input validation in application security?",
            "options": [
                "Ensuring that input data is safe and meets expected criteria",
                "Encrypting data",
                "Creating user interfaces",
                "Designing application architecture"
            ],
            "_answer": "Ensuring that input data is safe and meets expected criteria"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which technique is used to prevent SQL Injection attacks?",
            "options": [
                "Parameterize queries",
                "Use static code analysis",
                "Monitor application logs",
                "Encrypt data in transit"
            ],
            "_answer": "Parameterize queries"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the purpose of encryption in application security?",
            "options": [
                "Protecting data confidentiality and integrity",
                "Verifying user identities",
                "Logging application activity",
                "Simulating attacks"
            ],
            "_answer": "Protecting data confidentiality and integrity"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is an example of an authentication method?",
            "options": [
                "Password",
                "Input validation",
                "Encryption",
                "Logging"
            ],
            "_answer": "Password"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the 'Least Privilege Principle' in application security?",
            "options": [
                "Granting the minimum necessary permissions",
                "Using encryption for all data",
                "Conducting regular code reviews",
                "Simulating attack scenarios"
            ],
            "_answer": "Granting the minimum necessary permissions"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which common vulnerability involves injecting malicious scripts into web pages?",
            "options": [
                "SQL Injection",
                "Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)",
                "Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF)",
                "Buffer Overflow"
            ],
            "_answer": "Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)"
        }
    ]
}